In this video, we're going to talk about
car insurance renewal
tips, how it's renewed, and
what things you should keep
in mind. Normally,
you get 1+3 insurance on a new car.
1 year of on-damage insurance, and
3 years of third-party insurance, meaning
you have to renew from the second year. The
question that arises in people's minds is whether to
renew it online or through the showroom or dealership from where they purchased the car.
In this video,
you'll learn everything in detail.
Please watch the entire video,
and you'll find all the supporting links and
comparison links
in the description box. Let's
first discuss
which insurance is compulsory in India. Well,
only third-party
insurance is compulsory here, meaning that
if you don't pay the on-damage premium here and
don't take on-damage insurance, there's no
problem.  But brother,
you will have to take a third party. What
happens in third party is that if
you hit someone with your car, then the other
party gets a claim here. Also,
brother, I would like to tell you an interesting factor here. The
premium for third party insurance, no matter which company you get it from, will be the
same for everyone because ID has
fixed it here. So whatever
model number of your vehicle, etc., you
go to any company, that premium will always be
fixed for you. And brother,
under the on-damage premium, if
your car is stolen or damaged,
you get insurance here in all those cases.
Now,
before renewing your insurance, it is important to keep some points
in mind. The first most
important point is the IDV value
of the car and your premium is
decided on this basis. What is IDV value?
Depreciation keeps on applying on your car.
Now, if you want to check this, then
I will give you a link
in the description box. Simply put, you can find your IDV here.
Vakil type, your state, year,
in which month did you buy it, which maker,
which is the variant of your car, if
you enter all this then you
get the IDV value of your car here and brother,
if your car is more than 5 years old then
your deduction
starts at 50 percent. Now what is
special about the IDV value is that
you can increase or
decrease this IDV value. If you increase this value
here then your premium will
also increase here, if you
decrease then your premium will also decrease
but keep in mind that this is a
maximum value, if your car gets stolen
or gets total damage then only this
maximum liability is going to be given to
you, so
always keep in mind that do not reduce it by mistake
and do not increase it too much either.
You should always decide your premium here keeping in mind the IDV value of your actual car only.
Apart from this, guys, the second
factor is NCB
discount. What is NCB discount?
If you do not make any claim here in
any year and if you do not make any claim continuously for
5 years, then you
get NCB discount of 50%, that is, it starts getting applicable from the second year.
Suppose you did
not make any claim in the first year, then
you will get 20%, then if you did not make any claim in the second year also, then
you will get 25%, if you did not make any claim for 3 years,
then 35%, then 45% and if
you do not make any claim for 5 years, then it becomes 50%.
And brother, no matter which company you
take it from, you will always
get NCB discount here, that is,
whenever you check
your premium here, it will always ask you
whether you have made any insurance
claim before or how much NCB discount is there in your last policy.
So brother, according to this table, you
can select your NCB discount.
And here, brother, I would like to give a big pro tip,
many times people make this mistake if
₹5000000
Mostly you get this for 5 years, like when
you buy your new car, you
can consider zero depreciation for 5 years, but keep in
mind that this is a big factor in
increasing your premium, whenever
you select zero depreciation, your
premium almost doubles here,
as you can see in front of my screen,
right now my premium is
coming in the range of only 4 to 5000, but as soon as I
click on zero depreciation, it will
increase here, now brother, what does zero depreciation
mean here, so see here,
whenever your car breaks down, then when you go to get it repaired,
depreciation is charged on all the parts fitted inside it, so if I talk about glass parts here, then there is
no depreciation charged on them, but there is
30% depreciation on fiber class components and
50% depreciation on rubber, nylon, plastic, airbags, tyre tubes, batteries etc.
Depreciation is levied and as your car gets
older, if suppose your
car is more than 5 years old, then you will
start incurring depreciation of 50%, that is,
if any part is replaced in your car,
suppose the
bonnet of your car is broken and is being
replaced, the tyre is being replaced, then
brother,
you will have to pay the amount of depreciation from your pocket,
but brother, what is the amazing thing about this Ro Dab here is that
if you have a new
car, brother, then if you get Ro
Dab added in it, then you will
not have to pay any extra money from your pocket for
these parts, otherwise,
you will always have to pay the difference amount of depreciation, apart from this, the
insurance of your car which is
given to you by default, from
wherever you get the car released, there are
many advance covers in it,
for some it is necessary, for some
it is  Unnecessary advances are made here,
so you can save your premium here as well. For example,
if I talk about return
to invoice cover, suppose
your vehicle gets stolen, then you
get the invoice value, the original invoice
value instead of the IDV value.
Apart from this, brother, there is 24/7 roadside
assistance in it. If your
vehicle breaks down on the way, then
if you have taken this addon, call the company and they will
come to change your tyre or
fill petrol. If I
talk about engine protection cover, then
whatever is related to the engine is
protected here. So brother,
if you get this addon done, then your premium will
obviously increase. So
here you have to see whether this addon is
necessary for you or not.
Apart from this, guys, there is also a compulsory cover here
which is personal accident cover of
₹1 lakh. So see, whenever you
take a third party plan here or a
comprehensive plan also, then for that
Inside you can see that whenever you
want to checkout with any company, then
it is going to offer you a personal accidental cover
which is mandatory
but here I would like to tell that many people have
some such debit cards,
credit cards where
they have already got it,
these things are available in a good number of term plans also nowadays, so
you have to check if you have got it, then there is
no need to add it on, it is
obvious that you will save premium of ₹ 100 to ₹ 600,
apart from this brother you should see that how many cashless garages are there in
my nearby location
because what happens is that whenever your car gets damaged and
you have to make a claim etc. then first of all
your car will be
given cashless network facility here only, so
you have to check out which garages
or authorized centers of my car are
with this company, along with this
you will also have to see
that the company you are choosing
What is claim settlement ratio? So here
I have ICR report of IIDA,
it means that
how much premium has a company taken here within a year
and how much of that premium amount has been paid as a
claim here, here at
distributor, you can see it,
you will get it now, I will
also provide you the link of this PDF in the description box,
so you can see it is 86 of Ekko,
how do you have to renew your car insurance,
first thing if you are
satisfied with your previous company from where
you had already got insurance here,
then you can continue with that same company, I would like to
give an example,
what happens nowadays, suppose if
you have a Maruti car, then
I have to
make sure about the premium, that
brother, how much premium is coming, brother,
for that I would recommend, if you want, you can
check out the premium from Ekko's site here,
Policy Bazaar also offers this to you, it
also offers you on the phone, so
this is as much as  There are multiple sites here too,
first you should check that on
how much IDV value
I have to pay the premium here and
what benefits I am getting along with it,
so brother, majorly your premium is
always going to be based on the IDV value,
so the company which
provides you the best IDV value at the lowest premium with the best claim settlement ratio, brother,
you should basically consider them here
and if you want, you
can also check the pricing etc. from your dealer, but you should always
do a comparison
before renewing your insurance, so guys, hope
you like this video, all supported
links are in the description box, if you have
any doubts, please tell us in the comment box,
thank you guys, thank you very much